const physicsQuestions = [
  {
    question: "Work and energy are measured in Joule. The fundamental units involved in Joule are",
    options: [
      "(kg × m × m)/(s × s)",
      "(kg × m)/(s × s × s)",
      "kg/(m × m × m)",
      "(kg × m²)/(s²)"
    ],
    answer: "(kg × m²)/(s²)"
  },
  {
    question: "If mass of a body remains constant but its velocity is increased by 3 times, by how many times its kinetic energy increases?",
    options: [
      "3 times",
      "6 times",
      "9 times",
      "12 times"
    ],
    answer: "9 times"
  },
  {
    question: "If  and  represent the polar radius and equatorial radius of the earth and  and  are respective values of the acceleration due to gravity at those places, which of the following relation is true?",
    options: [
      "a.",
      "b.",
      "c.",
      "d. None of above"
    ],
    answer: "d. None of above"
  },
  {
    question: "Girls have shriller voice than boys because their voice possesses",
    options: [
      "Longer wavelength",
      "Shorter wavelength",
      "High pitch",
      "Low pitch"
    ],
    answer: "High pitch"
  },
  {
    question: "When light travels from denser medium to rarer medium, it does not obey laws of refraction, if",
    options: [
      "Angle of incidence is less than critical angle",
      "Angle of incidence is equal to critical angle",
      "Angle of incidence is greater than critical angle",
      "None of above"
    ],
    answer: "Angle of incidence is greater than critical angle"
  },
  {
    question: "Ray of which colour is found at bottom of a rainbow?",
    options: [
      "Blue",
      "Violet",
      "Red",
      "Yellow"
    ],
    answer: "Violet"
  },
  {
    question: "The expression to calculate resistance of a conductor is",
    options: [
      "RA",
      "R = V/I",
      "R = ρL/A",
      "R = IL/V"
    ],
    answer: "R = ρL/A"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following sentence is correct regarding magnetic lines of force?",
    options: [
      "They originate at north pole and terminate at south pole",
      "They are continuous",
      "They originate inside at south and end at north",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    answer: "All of the above"
  },
  {
    question: "An astronaut on the moon measures the mass of an object to be 1 kg. The result is:",
    options: [
      "1 kg",
      "6 kg",
      "3 kg",
      "0 kg"
    ],
    answer: "6 kg"
  },
  {
    question: "The mirrors used in vehicles to view behind are",
    options: [
      "Plane mirrors",
      "Concave mirrors",
      "Convex mirrors",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    answer: "Convex mirrors"
  },
  {
    question: "Among the following, which one is a fundamental unit?",
    options: [
      "Kelvin",
      "Ampere",
      "Candela",
      "All of above"
    ],
    answer: "All of above"
  },
  {
    question: "If distance between two particles is doubled, gravitational force becomes",
    options: [
      "Double",
      "Four times",
      "Half",
      "One fourth"
    ],
    answer: "One fourth"
  },
  {
    question: "A bus covers 20 km in 16 min 40 sec at 72 km/hr. Acceleration produced is",
    options: [
      "20 m/s²",
      "72 m/s²",
      "0 m/s²",
      "100 m/s²"
    ],
    answer: "0 m/s²"
  },
  {
    question: "If mass is doubled keeping distance constant, gravitational force becomes",
    options: [
      "Half",
      "Double",
      "One fourth",
      "Four times"
    ],
    answer: "Double"
  },
  {
    question: "On the moon, a coin and a feather are dropped together. Which hits first?",
    options: [
      "Coin",
      "Feather",
      "Both at same time",
      "None"
    ],
    answer: "Both at same time"
  },
  {
    question: "In freefall, acceleration is",
    options: [
      "Equal to gravity",
      "More than gravity",
      "Less than gravity",
      "Zero"
    ],
    answer: "Equal to gravity"
  },
  {
    question: "Value of gravity on moon is",
    options: [
      "9.8 m/s²",
      "1.6 m/s²",
      "m/s²",
      "10 m/s²"
    ],
    answer: "1.6 m/s²"
  },
  {
    question: "Value of universal gravitational constant G is",
    options: [
      "6.674*10............",
      "9.8 m/s²",
      "760 mmHg",
      "10 m/s²"
    ],
    answer: "6.674*10............"
  },
  {
    question: "Which is not a unit of pressure?",
    options: [
      "N/kg°C",
      "Pascal",
      "mm of Hg",
      "N/m²"
    ],
    answer: "N/kg°C"
  },
  {
    question: "Hydraulic machine works on",
    options: [
      "Pascal's law",
      "Archimedes' principle",
      "Law of floatation",
      "Newton's law"
    ],
    answer: "Pascal's law"
  },
  {
    question: "Device to measure atmospheric pressure:",
    options: [
      "Thermometer",
      "Seismograph",
      "Barometer",
      "Voltmeter"
    ],
    answer: "Barometer"
  },
  {
    question: "Normal atmospheric pressure is",
    options: [
      "760 mm of Hg",
      "Pa",
      "9.8 m/s²",
      "Both a and b"
    ],
    answer: "Both a and b"
  },
  {
    question: "A denser object floats in water when:",
    options: [
      "It is pressed",
      "It displaces water equal to its weight",
      "Its weight is decreased",
      "Surface area is decreased"
    ],
    answer: "It displaces water equal to its weight"
  },
  {
    question: "It is easier to lift bucket inside water because of:",
    options: [
      "Mass of water",
      "Volume of well water",
      "Upthrust",
      "Liquid pressure"
    ],
    answer: "Upthrust"
  },
  {
    question: "Solar energy received per m² per sec during day is",
    options: [
      "1.6 kW",
      "1.4 kW",
      "60 kW",
      "14 kW"
    ],
    answer: "1.4 kW"
  },
  {
    question: "Einstein’s mass-energy relation is",
    options: [
      "E = mc",
      "E = mc²",
      "E = Gmm/r²",
      "E = mgh"
    ],
    answer: "E = mc²"
  },
  {
    question: "Principle of hydrogen bomb is",
    options: [
      "Nuclear fission",
      "Displacement",
      "Nuclear fusion",
      "Archimedes’ principle"
    ],
    answer: "Nuclear fusion"
  },
  {
    question: "Principle of atom bomb is",
    options: [
      "Nuclear fission",
      "Displacement",
      "Nuclear fusion",
      "Schrödinger’s principle"
    ],
    answer: "Nuclear fission"
  },
  {
    question: "1 calorie =",
    options: [
      "8.2 J",
      "4.21 J",
      "1000 J",
      "4200 J"
    ],
    answer: "4200 J"
  },
  {
    question: "Total kinetic energy of molecules is called",
    options: [
      "Heat",
      "Temperature",
      "Specific heat capacity",
      "Heat equation"
    ],
    answer: "Heat"
  },
  {
    question: "Reciprocal of focal length (in meter) is",
    options: [
      "Power of lens",
      "Magnification",
      "Accommodation",
      "Principal axis"
    ],
    answer: "Power of lens"
  },
  {
    question: "Virtual image by convex lens is",
    options: [
      "Diminished",
      "Erect and magnified",
      "Inverted",
      "Opposite side"
    ],
    answer: "Erect and magnified"
  },
  {
    question: "Hypermetropia occurs due to",
    options: [
      "Elongated eye",
      "Thick eye lens",
      "Shortened eye ball",
      "Decrease in focal length"
    ],
    answer: "Shortened eye ball"
  },
  {
    question: "Electricity consumption formula is",
    options: [
      "P = IV",
      "P = W/t",
      "P × N × T",
      "N/N – V/N₂"
    ],
    answer: "P = W/t"
  },
  {
    question: "Heating element is",
    options: [
      "Chromium",
      "Nickel",
      "Nichrome",
      "Copper"
    ],
    answer: "Nichrome"
  },
  {
    question: "Gas in filament lamp is",
    options: [
      "Oxygen",
      "Nitrogen",
      "Ammonia",
      "Hydrogen"
    ],
    answer: "Nitrogen"
  },
  {
    question: "Derived unit is",
    options: [
      "Kelvin",
      "Mole",
      "Hertz",
      "Candela"
    ],
    answer: "Hertz"
  },
  {
    question: "Mass per unit volume is",
    options: [
      "Weight",
      "Velocity",
      "Work",
      "Density"
    ],
    answer: "Density"
  },
  {
    question: "Rate of change of displacement is",
    options: [
      "Distance",
      "Displacement",
      "Wavelength",
      "Mass"
    ],
    answer: "Displacement"
  },
  {
    question: "Physical quantity that depends on inertia",
    options: [
      "Acceleration",
      "Weight",
      "Force",
      "Mass"
    ],
    answer: "Mass"
  },
  {
    question: "Example of wheel and axle:",
    options: [
      "Staircase",
      "Screwdriver",
      "Scissors",
      "Nut-cracker"
    ],
    answer: "Screwdriver"
  },
  {
    question: "Mechanical advantage is ratio of",
    options: [
      "Two forces",
      "Two works",
      "Two distances",
      "Two loads"
    ],
    answer: "Two forces"
  },
  {
    question: "Turning effect of force is called",
    options: [
      "Efficiency",
      "Mechanical advantage",
      "Velocity ratio",
      "Moment"
    ],
    answer: "Moment"
  },
  {
    question: "Law of moment in balanced condition",
    options: [
      "E × L_d = L × E_d",
      "E × E_d = L × L_d",
      "E/E_d = L/L_d",
      "E/L_d = E_d/L"
    ],
    answer: "E × E_d = L × L_d"
  },
  {
    question: "100% efficiency is found in",
    options: [
      "Hydraulic machine",
      "Perfect machine",
      "Simple machine",
      "Compound machine"
    ],
    answer: "Perfect machine"
  },
  {
    question: "Energy due to flow of charge is",
    options: [
      "Magnetic",
      "Potential",
      "Atomic",
      "Electrical"
    ],
    answer: "Electrical"
  },
  {
    question: "Potential energy formula is",
    options: [
      "mc/h",
      "Nma",
      "mgh",
      "mv"
    ],
    answer: "mgh"
  },
  {
    question: "Unit of power is",
    options: [
      "Hp",
      "W",
      "N",
      "Both a and b"
    ],
    answer: "Both a and b"
  },
  {
    question: "In green plant, energy conversion is",
    options: [
      "Chemical → Heat",
      "Light → Chemical",
      "Light → Heat",
      "Chemical → Light"
    ],
    answer: "Light → Chemical"
  },
  {
    question: "Energy in stored water in dam",
    options: [
      "Kinetic",
      "Potential",
      "Chemical",
      "Both a and b"
    ],
    answer: "Potential"
  },
  {
    question: "Velocity tripled = KE increases by",
    options: [
      "3 times",
      "6 times",
      "9 times",
      "12 times"
    ],
    answer: "9 times"
  },
  {
    question: "Cause of sound intensity",
    options: [
      "Wavelength",
      "Frequency",
      "Amplitude",
      "Time"
    ],
    answer: "Amplitude"
  },
  {
    question: "Frequency of sound is",
    options: [
      "Complete waves in longitudinal",
      "Complete waves in transverse",
      "Complete waves per second",
      "Time to form one wave"
    ],
    answer: "Complete waves per second"
  },
  {
    question: "To make music melodious:",
    options: [
      "Reverberation",
      "Echo",
      "Refraction",
      "Diffraction"
    ],
    answer: "Reverberation"
  },
  {
    question: "Minimum distance for echo:",
    options: [
      "14 m",
      "15 m",
      "16 m",
      "17 m"
    ],
    answer: "17 m"
  },
  {
    question: "Speed of light in vacuum:",
    options: [
      "3×10⁵ km/s",
      "2.2×10⁸ m/s",
      "3×10⁸ m/s",
      "3×10² cm/s"
    ],
    answer: "3×10⁸ m/s"
  },
  {
    question: "Dispersion is effect of",
    options: [
      "Refraction",
      "Reflection",
      "Total internal reflection",
      "None"
    ],
    answer: "Refraction"
    
  },
  {
    question: "Colour with highest speed in medium",
    options: [
      "Blue",
      "Violet",
      "Orange",
      "Red"
    ],
    answer: "Red"
  },
  {
    question: "Object becomes hot after absorbing",
    options: [
      "UV rays",
      "Infrared rays",
      "X-rays",
      "Gamma rays"
    ],
    answer: "Infrared rays"
  },
  {
    question: "Highest refractive index",
    options: [
      "Glycerin",
      "Diamond",
      "Paraffin",
      "Water"
    ],
    answer: "Diamond"
  },
  {
    question: "Rate of flow of charge",
    options: [
      "Voltage",
      "Electric current",
      "Resistance",
      "Conductivity"
    ],
    answer: "Electric current"
  },
  {
    question: "If wire length increases, resistance:",
    options: [
      "Decreases",
      "No change",
      "Increases",
      "Irregular"
    ],
    answer: "Increases"
  },
  {
    question: "Angle between geographic & magnetic north",
    options: [
      "Magnetic meridian",
      "Geographic meridian",
      "Angle of declination",
      "Angle of dip"
    ],
    answer: "Angle of declination"
  },
  {
    question: "Where angle of dip is zero?",
    options: [
      "Geographic North",
      "Magnetic North",
      "Geographic South",
      "Equator"
    ],
    answer: "Equator"
  },
  {
    question: "Factor not affecting resistance",
    options: [
      "Thickness",
      "Type",
      "Pressure",
      "Temperature"
    ],
    answer: "Pressure"
  },
  {
    question: "1/ρ gives",
    options: [
      "Resistivity",
      "Conductivity",
      "Current",
      "Resistance"
    ],
    answer: "Conductivity"
  },
  {
    question: "When north pole is inclined north, neutral points lie",
    options: [
      "Sides",
      "Ends",
      "Center",
      "A & B both"
    ],
    answer: "Sides"
  },
  {
    question: "Time period of simple pendulum:",
    options: [
      "T = 2π√(l/g)",
      "T = 2π√(g/l)",
      "T = 1/(2π)√(l/g)",
      "T = 1/(2π)√(g/l)"
    ],
    answer: "T = 2π√(l/g)"
  },
  {
    question: "Most energetic among rays:",
    options: [
      "α-ray",
      "β-ray",
      "γ-ray",
      "X-ray"
    ],
    answer: "γ-ray"
  }
];
